Sravani Gurram React JS Developer

■ gurramsravani19@gmail.com ## https://srvnigrm.vercel.app

+91 9390435305 in linkedin.com/in/sravani-g-1193131b0

Pune, India https://github.com/34sravani-g

SUMMARY

Seasoned React JS Developer with over 1.5 years of experience, specialized in tackling tasks related to performance enhancements, and workflow optimizations. Ability to build and maintain intricate web applications, delivering tasks on time in fast-paced environments.

SKILLS

React.Js | JavaScript | HTML5 | CSS3 | BootStrap | NextJs | Git | Redux | Unit Testing(Jest, RTL) |

TypeScript | Node.js | Express.js | MongoDB | GraphQL | OOPS | DSA | Java | Python(basic)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Accenture

Associate Software Engineer

 Working as frontend developer in a project, developing reusable components using NextJS, React, GraphQL, Jest.

• Trained and certified in MERN Application Engg School.

Avegen

Software Engineer

• Led efforts to enhance app performance, resulting in a 100% reduction in card load times, greatly improving user satisfaction.

• Actively participated in client presentations and across team, worked on creating UI parts of template apps and related API.

Cognizant

Programmer Trainee Intern

• Designed and implemented user dashboard, authentication pages, writing comprehensive unit tests.

• Trained and certified in React Full stack development.

May 2023 – Aug 2024 Hyderabad, India

Aug 2023 – Feb 2024 Pune, India

Feb 2024 – present

Pune, India

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science,

Matrusri Engineering College, Hyderabad

2019 - 2023

Hyderabad

PROJECTS

Portfolio

- Tech Stack: Next.js, TypeScript, Tailwind.CSS, Resend, Vercel.
- Personal portfolio website developed with T3 stack, featuring Resend SDK integration for email transactions, hosted on Vercel with a streamlined build pipeline.

BookCart

- Tech Stack: React.js, MongoDB, Express.js, Node.js.
- Built a fully authenticated Ecommerce site which allows users for buying books with conditional searching, integrated payment gateway with paypal and card payment.

Sorting Visualizer

- Tech Stack: React.js, Redux, Algorithms.
- Implemented an application for visualizing sorting algorithms and pathfinding algorithms.

CERTIFICATIONS

Application Engg School-MERN, Accenture

Cloud Foundation School-Azure, Accenture

Problem Solving, DSA, SQL, Python certified, *HackerRank, GeeksForGeeks*